Reporting to the two officials,
أبلغ سيادتكما.
The rebel Feng Chen was shot in the abdomen,
المجرم فنغ تشن أصيب بطلق ناري في بطنه.
but his life is not in danger.
لكنه لم يصب بجروح مميتة.
As for his Nightmare Palm technique,
أما بالنسبة لقبضته السحرية،
it has been treated by Miss Qing Dai.
فقد عالجتها الآنسة تشينغ داي.
He has now been imprisoned in the imperial dungeon
وقد تم سجنه في السجن الإمبراطوري.
awaiting interrogation.
في انتظار الاستجواب.
Good.
حسنا.
The case of the Blue Demon has been solved.
لقد تم حل قضية الشيطان الأزرق.
Commander Mo,
الجنرال مو،
you've put righteousness above family ties.
لقد ضحى بعلاقاته العائلية من أجل العدالة.
You deserve the highest merit.
يجب أن يحصل على الفضل الأول.
Thanks to Commander Mo for sending me the message.
بفضل الرسالة التي أرسلها لي الجنرال مو،
I had long suspected there was something wrong with Feng Chen,
كنت قد شككت في فنغ تشن منذ فترة طويلة.
but I never imagined
لكنني لم أتخيل
he would try to control all court officials with his demonic palm technique.
أنه كان يخطط للسيطرة على جميع مسؤولي البلاط باستخدام قبضته السحرية.
It's even more despicable than the Blue Demon thief from years ago.
إنه أكثر بغضا من اللص الأزرق العظيم في الماضي.
Both of you, sirs, have a profound sense of justice.
سيادتكما على دراية عميقة بالعدالة.
My master and junior brother
أستاذي وأخي الأصغر في التدريب
in the underworld
في العالم السفلي
should be able to rest in peace now.
يمكنهما الآن أن يرقدا في سلام.
Tomorrow,
غدا
I will report to the imperial court
سأرفع تقريرا إلى البلاط الإمبراطوري
to exonerate General He
لتبرئة الجنرال هي.
I will also recommend you, Commander Mo, for a commendation.
سأطلب أيضا مكافأة لك، أيها الجنرال مو.
You will take over General He's position as the commander-in-chief.
ستتولى منصب المشرف العام بدلا من الجنرال هي من الآن فصاعدا.
Not only should we commend Commander Mo,
ليس فقط طلب المكافأة للجنرال مو،
but also Commander Xiao and Miss Qing Dai.
بل أيضا للجنرال شياو والآنسة تشينغ داي.
She is my lifesaver, after all.
إنها منقذة حياتي.
Thank you both, sirs.
شكرا جزيلا لسيادتكما.
Oh, by the way,
بالمناسبة،
where is Miss Qing Dai now?
أين الآنسة تشينغ داي الآن؟
Thank you, Sister Yunr.
شكرا لك يا أختي يون إر.
It's been so long since I've had this lotus tea.
لم أشرب شاي مينغ هي هذا منذ فترة طويلة.
This matter has come to an end.
لقد انتهى هذا الأمر.
What are your plans for the future?
ما هي خططك للمستقبل؟
Sister Yunr, do you want me to leave?
هل تريدين مني أن أرحل يا أختي يون إر؟
Sit down.
اجلسي بسرعة.
I want to leave this place of right and wrong.
أريد أن أغادر هذا المكان المليء بالمشاكل.
But hasn't everything been settled?
ولكن ألم تنته كل الأمور بالفعل؟
Feng Chen has been brought to justice.
فينغ تشن قد نال عقابه.
The truth has come to light.
والحقيقة قد ظهرت.
You and Brother Mo
أنت والأخ الكبير مو،
have also become a couple.
قد أصبحتما زوجين في النهاية.
If I stay here,
إذا بقيت هنا،
I can only be the owner of Sanxiang Teahouse.
فسأظل فقط صاحبة مقهى سان شيانغ للشاي.
Qing Dai.
تشينغ داي.
But I want to be Yunr again.
لكنني أريد أن أعود يون إر.
No matter who you are,
بغض النظر عمن تكونين،
from now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
I'll still be your little sister, Hong Guo.
سأظل أختك الصغرى هونغ قوه.
Is that okay?
هل هذا مقبول؟
No matter where you go,
أينما ذهبت،
as long as you and Brother Mo
طالما أنت والأخ الكبير مو
don't mind me tagging along.
لا تعتبراني عبئا عليكما.
Uncle He,
عم هي.
I am Qing Dai.
أنا تشينغ داي.
I buried you next to my mother.
دفنتك بجانب أمي.
You two, master and disciple,
أنتما الأخوان في التلمذة.
can now reunite in the afterlife.
يمكنكما الاجتماع في العالم الآخر.
Rest assured,
اطمئن.
I have mastered the hundred-word mantra of the Nightmare-Crushing Palm,
لقد تعلمت بالفعل المانترا المكونة من مائة حرف لتقنية تسوي يان زانغ.
and destroyed the Four Beauties Screen.
ودمرت أيضًا حاجز الجمال الأربعة.
No one will ever use it again.
لن يستخدمه أحد بعد الآن.
Master,
يا معلمي.
I am Mo Ze.
أنا مو زي.
I have resigned from my position in the patrol unit,
لقد استقلت من منصبي في فرقة الدوريات.
and I didn't take over the firearms unit.
ولم أتول قيادة فرقة الأسلحة النارية.
Please forgive me.
أرجو أن تسامحني.
There are more suitable candidates now.
هناك شخص أكثر ملاءمة الآن.
I just want to go to a new place with Yun'er,
أريد فقط أن أذهب إلى مكان جديد مع يون إر.
and start a new life.
لنبدأ حياة جديدة.
Benefactor,
يا محسني.
I am Hong Guo.
أنا هونغ قوه.
I will come to see you every Qingming Festival.
سآتي لزيارتك في عيد تشينغ مينغ كل عام.
I won't be wandering anymore.
لن أتشرد بعد الآن.
I have a family now too.
لدي عائلة الآن أيضًا.
The life-saving kindness you showed me years ago,
إحسانك بإنقاذ حياتي منذ سنوات عديدة.
I will always remember in my heart.
سأظل أتذكره دائمًا.
Xiao Wei,
شياو وي.
you must be watching me from somewhere, right?
أنت بالتأكيد تراقبني من مكان ما.
Thank you, Xiao Wei.
شكرًا لك يا شياو وي.
It was you who made me understand
أنت من جعلني أعرف.
what it feels like to be loved.
ما هو شعور أن تكون محبوبًا.
From now on, I will live well with this love.
سأعيش حياة جيدة مع هذا الحب في المستقبل.
Oh, right.
بالمناسبة.
If you run short of money over there,
إذا كنت بحاجة إلى المال هناك.
you must come to me in a dream.
يجب أن تأتي إلي في الحلم.
I won't be stingy with you, I promise.
لن أبخل عليك أبدًا.
They have gone ahead of us,
إنهم يسيرون أمامنا.
so we should also look forward.
لذلك علينا أن ننظر إلى الأمام أيضًا.
Let's go for a drink.
دعونا نذهب لشرب المشروبات.
You young people go by yourselves.
اذهبوا أنتم الشباب بأنفسكم.
As for me,
أما أنا.
I need to go home and try the lotus tea
فسأعود إلى المنزل لأتذوق.
that my daughter-in-law gave me.
شاي المينغ هي الذي أهدته لي زوجة ابني.
What about the wine?
ماذا عن المشروب؟
Yun'er can't drink alcohol.
يون إر لا تستطيع شرب الكحول.
Oh, oh, oh,
يا يا يا.
now you're calling her Yun'er directly.
الآن أصبحت تناديها يون إر مباشرة.
Let's make an exception today.
سنكسر القاعدة اليوم.
I've had someone deliver some wine.
لقد طلبت من شخص ما إحضار المشروب.
The wine is here.
وصل المشروب.
This is yours.
هذا لك.
Two jars in total.
إنهما جرتان في المجموع.
Thank you.
شكرًا.
The wine is here.
وصل المشروب.
Give it to me.
أعطني.
Where do we plan to go next?
إلى أين نخطط للذهاب في محطتنا التالية؟
Let's go to Jiangnan.
دعونا نذهب إلى جيانغنان.
I've never been there.
لم أذهب إلى هناك من قبل.
We can go boating on the lake,
يمكننا الإبحار في البحيرة.
and fish from the bridge.
ويمكننا صيد السمك على الجسر.
Or maybe Saibei,
أو ربما إلى سايبي.
galloping on horseback,
نركب الخيول ونجري بحرية.
free and unrestrained.
بكل حرية.
Come on,
هيا.
cheers!
نخب!
How many children do you two plan to have?
كم طفلاً تخططان لإنجابه في المستقبل؟
Maybe two,
اثنان ربما.
a boy and a girl.
ولد وبنت.
We'll choose good names for them.
نختار لهما أسماء جيدة.
That's not for you to decide.
هذا ليس قرارك.
Whether to have children or not,
سواء ننجب أم لا.
and how many to have,
وكم عددهم.
I'll be the one to decide.
أنا من سيقرر.
Linghua.
لينغ هوا.
Those eating snacks, drink.
من يأكل الحلوى يشرب.
Those swaying, drink.
من يهز جسده يشرب.
Hit.
أصبت.
You two, drink.
اشربا أنتما الاثنان.
Come on.
هيا.
It's my turn.
دوري الآن.
Wangchun.
وانغ تشون.
Those facing east, drink.
من يواجه الشرق يشرب.
I'm now taking over the Imperial Guard.
سأتولى إدارة قسم الحماية الآن.
If you could pass on the Crushing Nightmare Palm technique to me.
إذا استطعت أن تنقل لي مهارة كف تسوي يان.
I promise to spare your life.
أعدك بأن أترك لك حياتك.
Yi Chu Pin Yi
إنتاج واحد.
Beijing National Fashion Culture Communication Co., Ltd.
شركة بكين الوطنية للثقافة والإعلام المحدودة.
Horgos Daobo Spring Film and Television Culture Media Co., Ltd.
شركة هورغوس داوبو تشونتيان للثقافة والإعلام المرئي والمسموع المحدودة.
- Production -
- إنتاج -
- Art Director -
- الإشراف الفني -
You Jianming
يو جيان مينغ
- Cast -
- قائمة الممثلين -
Baidian Pictures
باي ديان للأفلام
Visual Effects Production
إنتاج المؤثرات البصرية
Yan Ruhua
يان رو هوا
Music Production
إنتاج الموسيقى
Beijing Landuo Music
موسيقى لاندو بكين